Mak Mendelson

SUMMARY

Having gone through the experience of co-founding, managing, and developing products at a small video game company for nearly four years, I'm looking to continue improving my abilities so as to one day return to the game industry.

My current focus is to improve my skills in User Interface and User Experience Design at Buchanan & Edwards.

SKILLS

- User Interface Design
- User Experience Design
- User Experience Testing
- Product Development
- Game Design
- Game Development
- Graphic Design
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- 2D & 3D Animation
- 3D Modeling
- Texturing
- Blender
- Digital Art
- Conceptual Art
- Fine Art

EXPERIENCE

December 2014 - Present

Buchanan & Edwards

http://buchanan-edwards.com/

User Interface Consultant and Tester

- Consulted for, generated high-fidelity mock-ups for, and tested User Interfaces in the development of a Knowledge Management Tool web application for the Department of State.
- Worked closely with Business Analysts to collect, define, and document client requirements.
- Worked closely with Developers to determine best implementation strategies, and to ensure the product is inline with current design mock-ups.
- Developed branding and identity for a separate project.
- I currently hold an active DOD SECRET clearance

April 2010 - February 2014

Gradient Studios

http://www.gradientstudios.com/

Co-Founder and Visual Artist

- Founded right out of college.
- · Team's primary artist and asset creator in all art related fields.
- Integral involvement in product design and development from beginning to end of projects.
- Gradient Studios prospered for nearly 4 years through a mix of contract work, some angel investments, and, eventually, a round of seed funding.
- Ultimately the company went under, but I learned a lot from my experience

August 2006 - May 2010

Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute

Helpdesk Consultant

Provided Software Support at the Computer Center

EDUCATION

2006 - 2010

Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute

BS, Games & Simulation Arts & Sciences, Concentration in Electronic Arts

• Theta Xi, Shorinjiryu Watanabe-Ha Karate-Do, Kendo, Game Development Club, Helpdesk

2002 - 2006

Gilman School

High School Diploma

INTERESTS

Drawing, Board games, Video games, Google Spreadsheets, Martial Arts, Skiing, Beer

ASSOCIATIONS

Boston Blender Users Group, Boston Indies, Boston Post-Mortem IGDA Chapter

LANGUAGES

- English (Native)
- Russian (Fluent)
- Spanish (Intermediate)